# Priyank Solanki

# Mean-stack Developer

Ahmedabad.

Gujarat, IN 380051

: (+91) 97268 68355

: priyanksolanki30197@gmail.com

: https://priyank-solanki.co.uk

: https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyank-solanki-320578102/

# **ABOUT ME**

Experienced programmer, and technology consultant with having demonstrated history of working on a wide variety of technologies from backend in PHP, Laravel, and CakePHP to frontend in Angular, and React, to hybrid mobile technology like flutter.

I am obsessed with security for API and Data, performance, development best practices, DevOps, and love for languages, JavaScript, PHP, Android, and Flutter.

# SKILLS ( Prefer & Mainly Used )

#### **Frontend**

- React
- Angular
- Bootstrap

#### **Backend**

- Laravel
- CakePHP

#### Hybrid

Flutter

#### **DevOps**

- Jenkins
- SonarQube
- WSL

#### Corporate

- Agile
- Project Lead
- Time Management

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Consumer Sketch - Website & App Development Company, India

- Mean-Stack Developer

February 2022 - PRESENT

# BiztechCS, India

- Junior Software Engineer

July 2019 - February 2022

- Work both independently and as a member of a team on development projects and work to provide quality solutions that meet specific business requirements using business and technical knowledge to help prevent defects.
- Independently create the design, coding, and testing of complex technical solutions.
- Applied software design skills to develop and maintain features using object-oriented methodologies.
- Contributed to Research & Development related to the Technology
- Undertaken the testing and debugging of applications.
- Solved issues given by QA and check its compliance.
- Identify / Escalate the risks and issues to the Supervisor on a regular basis.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Charotar University of Science and Technology, India

- MCA (Master of Computer Applications)

July 2017 - July 2019

I had an achievement of 8.00 CGPA with good knowledge of the different kinds of languages for my good corporate career

#### Charotar University of Science and Technology, India

- BCA (Bachelor of Computer Applications)

July 2014 - July 2017

I achieved a 6.75 CGPA with good knowledge of practicals. Also, I got different viewpoints for achieving my future goal.

# **PROJECTS**

#### WatchO & DCLeake

- Project under Consumer Sketch

April 2022 - Current

Both sites are using BigCommerce which is a NASDAQ-listed eCommerce platform that provides software as a service to retailers. The company's platform includes online store creation, search engine optimization, hosting, and marketing and security for small to enterprise businesses. WatchO & DCLeake are the online stores that the Client handles and we have to customization the theme and do some logic for custom functionalities. BigCommerce's theme is working with the Handlebar JS.

# **IgoWok**

- Project under Consumer Sketch

February 2022 - April 2022

IgoWok is a site where you can advertise jobs and search for resumes. They are an integral part of almost every hiring process and using them effectively will translate into qualified candidates for relatively low costs. IgoWork is developing into ReactJS with Laravel API.

# InCTRL - opsCTRL

- Project under BiztechCS

January 2020 - January 2022

Waste Management App Supplier and facility - inCTRL Solutions works hard to help you better understand, manage and optimize your technology and facility's performance. We are specialists in water, wastewater, and biogas.opsCTRL is a Connected Data, Asset, and Knowledge Management Solution built for facility operators.

#### PME & PA

- Project under BiztechCS

July 2019 - January 2020

Proofread My Essay is a UK-based company that offers quality proofreading services to students, professionals as well as business owners. Initially, the company used to work with students and offered a "Pay as you go" option. It recently came up with the "Pay upon invoice" option for businesses and organizations so that they can submit bulk work and documents for proofreading. BiztechCS developed the company's website cum web application with custom modules, payment gateway, and other integrations.

#### **Personal Card Holder**

- Personal Idea

Covid Period

In this project, I tried to manage all the personal documents with their images and passwords. I used the JSON and the master passwords in this project as authentication.

# **Counseling Management System**

- Project of MCA

July 2018

In this project, We tried to manage the leaves & personal questions of students and make the whole counseling management system in an android application with Core PHP API. We managed the four types of user roles like Super Admin, Admin, Faculty, and Student.

# **Leave Management System**

Project of BCA

July 2016

This project provides information about leave to different users and also employees can view leave, take leave, and delete the leave.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Served as a volunteer of NGO "NIRMAAN" which worked to educate poor children
- Served as a volunteer of CREDP (Charusat Rural Education Development Program)
- Completed the course "Programming in C"
- Senior volunteer of Tech. Fest
- Volunteer of EOC (Equal Opportunity Cell)

#### **PARTICIPATION**

- Participated in SIGHT-N-ERROR on Cognizance-2014 (Technical Festival) at CSPIT, CHARUSAT
- Attended Android Workshop on 13th -14th February 2015 at CMPICA, CHARUSAT
- Participated in the "WD (HTML, CSS)" technical event on Ignite-2015 (Technical Festival) at CMPICA, CHARUSAT
- Participated in "Quick Page" and "Let's Click" technical events at Ignite-2016 (Technical Festival) at CMPICA, CHARUSAT.

# **LANGUAGE**

- English
- Hindi
- Gujarati

#### **HOBBIES**

- Photography
- Bike Riding
- Video Gaming